<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rdap-query-purpose-values.xsl"?>
<?xml-model href="rdap-query-purpose-values.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0" ?>
<registry xmlns="http://www.iana.org/assignments" id="rdap-query-purpose-values">
  <title>Registration Data Access Protocol (RDAP) Query Purpose Values</title>
  <category>Registration Data Access Protocol (RDAP)</category>
  <created>2023-11-09</created>
  <updated>2023-11-09</updated>
  
  <registry id="rdap-query-purpose-values">
    <title>Registration Data Access Protocol (RDAP) Query Purpose Values</title>
    <xref type="draft" data="RFC-ietf-regext-rdap-openid-27"/>
    <registration_rule>Specification Required</registration_rule>
    <expert>Unassigned</expert>

    <record date="2023-11-09">
      <value>domainNameControl</value>
      <description>Tasks within the scope of this purpose include 
        creating and managing and monitoring a registrant's own domain name, 
        including creating the domain name, updating information about the 
        domain name, transferring the domain name, renewing the domain name, 
        deleting the domain name, maintaining a domain name portfolio, and 
        detecting fraudulent use of the Registrant's own contact information.
      </description>
      <xref type="draft" data="RFC-ietf-regext-rdap-openid-27"/>
    </record>

    <record date="2023-11-09">
      <value>personalDataProtection</value>
      <description>Tasks within the scope of this purpose include identifying 
        the accredited privacy/proxy provider associated with a domain name 
        and reporting abuse, requesting reveal, or otherwise contacting the 
        provider.
      </description>
      <xref type="draft" data="RFC-ietf-regext-rdap-openid-27"/>
    </record>

    <record date="2023-11-09">
      <value>technicalIssueResolution</value>
      <description>Tasks within the scope of this purpose include (but are not 
        limited to) working to resolve technical issues, including email 
        delivery issues, DNS resolution failures, and website functional issues.
      </description>
      <xref type="draft" data="RFC-ietf-regext-rdap-openid-27"/>
    </record>

    <record date="2023-11-09">
      <value>domainNameCertification</value>
      <description>Tasks within the scope of this purpose include a Certification 
        Authority (CA) issuing an X.509 certificate to a subject identified by a 
        domain name.
      </description>
      <xref type="draft" data="RFC-ietf-regext-rdap-openid-27"/>
    </record>

    <record date="2023-11-09">
      <value>individualInternetUse</value>
      <description>Tasks within the scope of this purpose include identifying 
        the organization using a domain name to instill consumer trust, or 
        contacting that organization to raise a customer complaint to them 
        or file a complaint about them.
      </description>
      <xref type="draft" data="RFC-ietf-regext-rdap-openid-27"/>
    </record>

    <record date="2023-11-09">
      <value>businessDomainNamePurchaseOrSale</value>
      <description>Tasks within the scope of this purpose include making 
        purchase queries about a domain name, acquiring a domain name 
        from a registrant, and enabling due diligence research.
      </description>
      <xref type="draft" data="RFC-ietf-regext-rdap-openid-27"/>
    </record>

    <record date="2023-11-09">
      <value>academicPublicInterestDNSResearch</value>
      <description>Tasks within the scope of this purpose include academic 
        public interest research studies about domain names published in 
        the registration data service, including public information about 
        the registrant and designated contacts, the domain name's history 
        and status, and domain names registered by a given registrant 
        (reverse query).
      </description>
      <xref type="draft" data="RFC-ietf-regext-rdap-openid-27"/>
    </record>

    <record date="2023-11-09">
      <value>legalActions</value>
      <description>Tasks within the scope of this purpose include investigating 
        possible fraudulent use of a registrant's name or address by other domain 
        names, investigating possible trademark infringement, contacting a 
        registrant/licensee's legal representative prior to taking legal 
        action and then taking a legal action if the concern is not 
        satisfactorily addressed.
      </description>
      <xref type="draft" data="RFC-ietf-regext-rdap-openid-27"/>
    </record>

    <record date="2023-11-09">
      <value>regulatoryAndContractEnforcement</value>
      <description>Tasks within the scope of this purpose include tax authority 
        investigation of businesses with online presence, Uniform Dispute 
        Resolution Policy (UDRP) investigation, contractual compliance 
        investigation, and registration data escrow audits.
      </description>
      <xref type="draft" data="RFC-ietf-regext-rdap-openid-27"/>
    </record>

    <record date="2023-11-09">
      <value>criminalInvestigationAndDNSAbuseMitigation</value>
      <description>Tasks within the scope of this purpose include reporting abuse 
        to someone who can investigate and address that abuse, or contacting 
        entities associated with a domain name during an offline criminal 
        investigation.
      </description>
      <xref type="draft" data="RFC-ietf-regext-rdap-openid-27"/>
    </record>

    <record date="2023-11-09">
      <value>dnsTransparency</value>
      <description>Tasks within the scope of this purpose involve querying the 
        registration data made public by registrants to satisfy a wide variety 
        of use cases around informing the public.
      </description>
      <xref type="draft" data="RFC-ietf-regext-rdap-openid-27"/>
    </record>

  </registry>
  
  <people>
  </people>
</registry>
