<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="collation.xsl"?>
<?xml-model href="collation.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0" ?>
<registry xmlns="http://www.iana.org/assignments" id="collation">
  <title>Collation Registry for Internet Application Protocols</title>
  <hide/>
  <updated>2013-08-20</updated>
  <registration_rule>Expert Review</registration_rule>
  <description><xref type="rfc" data="rfc4790"/> creates an abstraction framework so that application protocols
can precisely identify a comparison function and the repertoire of comparison
functions can be extended in the future. This document defines an IANA-maintained 
registry of collations for comparing, searching and sorting international strings.
</description>
  <record>
    <value>i;ascii-numeric</value>
    <description>The "i;ascii-numeric" collation is a simple collation intended
      for use with arbitrary sized unsigned decimal integer numbers stored as
      octet strings. US-ASCII digits (0x30 to 0x39) represent digits of the
      numbers. Before converting from string to integer, the input string is
      truncated at the first non-digit character. All input is valid; strings
      which do not start with a digit represent positive infinity.</description>
    <xref type="rfc" data="rfc4790"/>
  </record>
  <record>
    <value>i;ascii-casemap</value>
    <description>The "i;ascii-casemap" collation is a simple collation which
      operates on octet strings and treats US-ASCII letters case-insensitively.
      It provides equality, substring and ordering operations. All input is
      valid. Note that letters outside ASCII are not treated case-
      insensitively.</description>
    <xref type="rfc" data="rfc4790"/>
  </record>
  <record>
    <value>i;octet</value>
    <description>The "i;octet" collation is a simple and fast collation intended
      for use on binary octet strings rather than on character data. Protocols
      that want to make this collation available have to do so by explicitly
      allowing it. If not explicitly allowed, it MUST NOT be used. It never
      returns an "undefined" result. It provides equality, substring and
      ordering operations.</description>
    <xref type="rfc" data="rfc4790"/>
  </record>
  <record>
    <value>i;unicode-casemap</value>
    <description>
      <paragraph>The "i;unicode-casemap" collation is a simple collation which
        is case-insensitive in its treatment of characters. It provides
        equality, substring, and ordering operations. The validity test
        operation returns "valid" for any input.</paragraph>
      <paragraph>This collation allows strings in arbitrary (and mixed)
        character sets, as long as the character set for each string is
        identified and it is possible to convert the string to Unicode. Strings
        which have an unidentified character set and/or cannot be converted to
        Unicode are not rejected, but are treated as binary.</paragraph>
    </description>
    <xref type="rfc" data="rfc5051"/>
  </record>
  <people/>
</registry>
